<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://www.haloneuro.com/blogs/halo.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.haloneuro.com/blogs/halo"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.haloneuro.com/blogs/halo/tagged/learn-guitar-in-8-weeks.atom"/>
  <title>Halo Neuroscience - Halo Neuroscience Blog</title>
  <updated>2019-09-12T09:00:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Halo Neuroscience</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.haloneuro.com/blogs/halo/what-i-accomplished-in-just-8-weeks-with-halo-sport</id>
    <published>2019-08-23T10:34:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2019-08-26T15:05:59-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.haloneuro.com/blogs/halo/what-i-accomplished-in-just-8-weeks-with-halo-sport"/>
    <title>What I Accomplished in Just 8 Weeks with Halo Sport</title>
    <author>
      <name>Alyse Brown</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<meta charset="utf-8">8 weeks ago, I didn’t know how to play the guitar... at all. Today, I just performed in front of 50 people. And I couldn’t have done it without Halo Sport 2 — the brain stimulator that’s given me the confidence to achieve my goals. What can you do in 8 weeks?<p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.haloneuro.com/blogs/halo/what-i-accomplished-in-just-8-weeks-with-halo-sport">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h4><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/64UCpl2CUYU" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></h4>
<h4>An overview of the goals I achieved with Halo Sport 2.</h4>
<p><em>Welcome back! My name is Alyse, and I'm conquering my fears by learning guitar — in just 8 weeks. If you want to witness my journey from start to finish, read my first three blogs <a href="https://www.haloneuro.com/learn-guitar" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>.</em></p>
<p>Click, click. Whoosh. There was nowhere to go but forward. My stomach filled with butterflies as I braced for what was about to come.</p>
<p>You know that feeling you get on a roller coaster? The one where the bar clicks down on your lap and you realize there's no escaping. You’re filled with fear as the clicking sound of chains pushes you up the mountain... then suddenly you’re flying.</p>
<p>That’s the feeling I’ve had with <a href="https://www.haloneuro.com/products/halo-sport-2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Halo Sport</a> this summer. Trying new things is <i>terrifying</i>. What if I fail? What if I tell everyone I'm going to do it... and then I can’t? Disappointment has always been my greatest fear. But you know what? I finally faced my fears. <strong>Not only did I learn guitar, but I also tried aerial yoga, cycled my way to the front of spin class, and most recently broke my record at Flywheel by achieving 7th place.</strong></p>
<p>Throughout my journey, I tried to track my progress scientifically. I learned some chords with real Halo Sport 2 stimulation, and some chords with placebo stimulation. Unfortunately, we chose the wrong measure to assess my performance, so the data came out <em>really</em> wonky. I'm bummed we couldn't quantify my learning, but I know that I've accomplished way more than I thought I could in just a few weeks.</p>
<p>My original goal was to learn two guitar pieces by the end of the summer, but I decided to raise the stakes and do a duet instead. Singing and playing the guitar at the same time is a tough task. So, adding another person into the mix? That was a major test of my newfound guitar skills <em>and</em> my multitasking abilities.</p>
<p>But I did it! I successfully performed “Dreams” by Fleetwood Mac in front of 50 people. I was SO nervous when I got up to the stage — sweat drops were literally dripping from my hands onto my guitar. But once I pushed through my nerves, I started to play... and you know what? It actually went really well! I definitely made some mistakes, but I felt confident up there... I never imagined I could feel like this playing guitar in front of so many people!</p>
<p>I’m so glad that I decided to take on this challenge 8 weeks ago, and I'm looking forward to continuing my guitar journey with Halo Sport. Maybe one day I'll even be able to shred like <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VYAoJ2QfKE0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Lindsey Buckingham</a>.</p>
I didn’t know how to play the guitar<i> at all </i>when I set out on this journey. Today, I just performed in front of 50 people. And I couldn’t have done it without <a href="https://www.haloneuro.com/products/halo-sport-2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Halo Sport 2</a> — the brain stimulator that’s given me the confidence to achieve my goals. <strong>What can you do in 8 weeks?</strong>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.haloneuro.com/blogs/halo/how-to-master-the-art-of-confidence</id>
    <published>2019-08-23T10:33:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2019-08-26T14:53:41-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.haloneuro.com/blogs/halo/how-to-master-the-art-of-confidence"/>
    <title>How I Mastered the Art of Confidence</title>
    <author>
      <name>Alyse Brown</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[A short story of how neuroscience helped me build the confidence to achieve my goals — and how it can help you too.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.haloneuro.com/blogs/halo/how-to-master-the-art-of-confidence">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h4><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RIsgjtIBmio" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></h4>
<h4>A short story of how neuroscience helped me build the confidence to achieve my goals — and how it can help you too.</h4>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Welcome back! My name is Alyse, and I'm conquering my fears by learning guitar — in just 8 weeks. If you missed my first two blogs, check them out <a href="https://www.haloneuro.com/learn-guitar" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>.<br></span></i></p>
<p>I could feel the blood rush to my head as my body flipped upside down, grasping at the fabric to find stability, and I thought to myself — is this what confidence is? </p>
<p>Hold on, let’s rewind. I’m <i>loving </i>the way <a href="https://www.haloneuro.com/products/halo-sport-2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Halo Sport</a> makes me feel. It’s given me a lot of confidence in my skills as a musician, and I can even sing and play the guitar at the same time now. YES! </p>
<p>Halo Sport has helped me build confidence in <i>so</i> many areas of my life. I love the rush of a good spin class, but I usually stick to the back row. Over these past few weeks, though, I’ve felt faster and stronger than ever — so now I’m choosing the front row bikes.</p>
<p>This week, I decided to really break out of my comfort zone — and take an aerial yoga class. Cardio is my love, but me and balance exercises? HAHA. Funny joke… so I slipped on my lululemon pants and ventured into the world of anti-gravity. </p>
<img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0037/7965/7840/files/IMG_1173_2_large.JPG?v=1566427406" style="float: right;">
<p>I showed up to the studio Primed and ready to go, where I was greeted by a nice lady who guided me through the entire class. She even gave me personal instructions on how to get a deeper stretch in my hips (which was honestly one of the most painful and liberating things I’ve ever experienced).</p>
<p>My proudest moment came when I did my first handstand — ever! I’ve never been able to do cartwheels or handstands, but today I finally succeeded — and it felt like I was flying (literally). There were some aerial pros in the class who definitely surpassed my abilities by a long shot, but it just felt good knowing that I had built up the confidence to actually follow through with something that I’ve wanted to do for years.</p>
<p>Physical fitness is important, but since using Halo Sport my relationship with fitness is what has really changed. I have the confidence to be in the front row at any class and even try crazy activities like aerial yoga! I’m doing things that I never dreamed I would actually do — all thanks to Halo Sport. And that’s how I mastered the art of confidence.</p>
<p>Series Finale: <a href="https://www.haloneuro.com/blogs/halo/what-i-accomplished-in-just-8-weeks-with-halo-sport">What I Accomplished in Just 8 Weeks with Halo Sport</a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.haloneuro.com/blogs/halo/3-hacks-for-beginner-musicians</id>
    <published>2019-08-23T10:32:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2019-08-26T14:43:46-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.haloneuro.com/blogs/halo/3-hacks-for-beginner-musicians"/>
    <title>3 Hacks for Beginner Musicians</title>
    <author>
      <name>Alyse Brown</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[A few need-to-know tricks for learning guitar — including how to optimize your brain with neuroscience.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.haloneuro.com/blogs/halo/3-hacks-for-beginner-musicians">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h4><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/4pBz2j5mOoI" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></h4>
<h4>A few need-to-know tricks for learning guitar — including how to optimize your brain with neuroscience.</h4>
<p><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">Welcome back! My name is Alyse, and I'm conquering my fears by learning guitar — in just 8 weeks. If you missed my first blog, check it out <a href="https://www.haloneuro.com/blogs/halo/how-to-learn-guitar-according-to-neuroscience">here</a>.</span></i></p>
<p>I have to admit I’m a little surprised... my mission to learn guitar is <i>a lot</i> of fun so far. I’m definitely not any good yet, but I’m not intimidated anymore. So that’s progress!</p>
<p>The bad part? The guitar has given me some wicked calluses and an odd numbing sensation in my fingers. But I Googled it and found that this should get better over time. So here’s to hoping the internet is right, at least for my fingers’ sake.</p>
<p>I’ve been practicing for a few weeks now, and I’ve picked up a few tips and tricks along the way. If you’re joining me on my journey and learning a new instrument with Halo Sport too, these tips are for you.</p>
<h4>1. What did you say, I can’t hear you. Chocolate?</h4>
<p>If you haven't seen <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=obBjKdhZ7-I" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">this famous SpongeBob episode</a>, you're definitely missing out. It was actually the very first thing I thought of when I started practicing with Halo Sport. Halo Sport is a brain stimulator <em>and</em> a high-end pair of headphones, which is awesome at the gym — you can get in the zone fast with your favorite workout jams.</p>
<p><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0037/7965/7840/files/Screen_Shot_2019-08-16_at_11.48.28_AM_medium.png?v=1566425176" style="float: right;">But musicians don’t need to tune out the world — actually, quite the opposite. That’s why the Halo Neuroscience team created <a href="https://www.haloneuro.com/collections/frontpage/products/open-ear-pads" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">open ear pads</a> — so you can hear almost as well as if you weren't wearing a headset at all. They were easy to install and made such a difference while practicing. If you plan on playing any type of instrument with Halo Sport, you need these ASAP.</p>
<h4>2. The wetter, the better</h4>
<p>When you start your first Neuropriming session, the <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/halo-sport/id1145104454" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Halo Sport app</a> prompts you to <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3Mk1RfVqWUo" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">wet your Primer Band</a>. Okay perfect, easy enough. </p>
<p style="float: right;">But when they say wet, they mean <em>wet</em>. It takes almost a full minute under the faucet for the Primer Band to be ready. If I’m struggling, 9 times out of 10, this is what’s causing my Priming troubles, so pro tip — the wetter, the better. </p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p style="float: right;">Side note: I also put my Halo Sport on backwards once. Life is complicated, but Priming isn’t. Just make sure to check the orientation of the headset when you put it on — a quick and easy fix.</p>
<p style="float: right;"> </p>
<p style="float: right;"> </p>
<p style="float: right;"> </p>
<h4>3. Consult YouTube</h4>
<p style="float: right;"><img alt="" src="//cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0037/7965/7840/files/Screen_Shot_2019-08-16_at_11.48.55_AM_large.png?v=1566425471" style="float: right;">Youtube: the place you go if you want to laugh, cry, or you just have a few hours to kill. It can lead you down a deep hole of procrastination, and it’s no surprise considering there are millions of videos on the platform.</p>
<p style="float: right;">But if you're feeling productive, you can learn pretty much anything with Youtube's vast video library. So of course, it's the first place I looked when I started my journey. Right now, I’m following along with YouTubers <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCBNkm8o5LiEVLxO8w0p2sfQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">JustinGuitar</a> and <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCMVcE4tPTXx5ILVjG_KOukg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">JamPlay</a> to learn guitar one video at a time. The best part? <strong>It's free!</strong></p>
<p style="float: right;"> </p>
<p>Try my tips and tricks out for yourself. And if you’re still debating whether to join me on my adventure, it’s not too late. Pick up that instrument and get started with <a href="https://www.haloneuro.com/products/halo-sport-2">Halo Sport 2</a> today!</p>
<p>Keep following along — next, see how I'm <a href="https://www.haloneuro.com/blogs/halo/how-to-master-the-art-of-confidence">mastering the art of confidence</a>.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://www.haloneuro.com/blogs/halo/how-to-learn-guitar-according-to-neuroscience</id>
    <published>2019-08-23T10:30:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2019-08-26T10:03:52-07:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.haloneuro.com/blogs/halo/how-to-learn-guitar-according-to-neuroscience"/>
    <title>How to Learn Guitar (According to Neuroscience)</title>
    <author>
      <name>Alyse Brown</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[Follow along as I learn guitar in just 8 weeks with Halo Sport 2, the brain stimulator for musicians.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://www.haloneuro.com/blogs/halo/how-to-learn-guitar-according-to-neuroscience">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h4><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HzS0OU6EewE" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></h4>
<h4>Follow along as I learn guitar in just 8 weeks with Halo Sport 2, the brain stimulator for musicians. </h4>
<p>Guitar has always terrified me. I’ve been singing since I was five years old, but using my hands to make music? That’s completely different.</p>
<p>This summer, I was looking for a challenge, so I partnered with Halo Neuroscience to face my fears and finally learn guitar. I’ll be using their headset, called <a href="https://www.haloneuro.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Halo Sport</a>, to accomplish my guitar goals. Halo Sport improves muscle memory through <a href="https://www.haloneuro.com/pages/science" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">neurostimulation</a> — which basically means I turn into a superhuman who can learn movement faster.</p>
<p>Like the name suggests, Halo Sport was originally built for <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AnzP5zX8rEo" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">athletes</a>. That is, until this <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fVUvgUSX9hU" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">concert pianist</a> discovered it — and learned a Bach prelude in only 1 hour. That’s what got me thinking... could Halo Sport help people trying to learn an instrument for the first time, too?</p>
<p>I’ll be putting this question to the test and using Halo Sport to learn guitar for the first time — in just 8 weeks. </p>
<p>I love the idea of bringing my guitar to a friend’s house and impressing everyone with my newfound skills. So, that’s my goal. I’ll be testing myself to see if I can learn two songs this summer: “Drive” by Oh Wonder and “Dreams” by Fleetwood Mac. Oh — and I’ll be performing them in just 8 weeks, so the pressure is on.</p>
<p>Here’s to starting my journey, let’s get to work!</p>
<p>Follow along as I start my adventure, and challenge yourself to learn a new instrument too. You never know what you could accomplish in just 8 weeks. Get <a href="https://www.haloneuro.com/products/halo-sport-2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Halo Sport</a> and start unlocking your inner musician today!</p>
<meta charset="utf-8">
<p>Next up: <a href="https://www.haloneuro.com/blogs/halo/3-hacks-for-beginner-musicians">3 Hacks for Beginner Musicians</a></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
